A journey into a world where legends come to life.
Dreams come true. And every boy is a hero.
Tall Tale: The Unbelievable Adventure is a adventure, family,
western film directed by Jeremiah S. Chechik.
A young boy draws on the inspiration of legendary western characters to find the strength to fight an evil land
baron in the old west who wants to steal his family's farm and destroy their idyllic community.
When Daniel Hackett sees his father Jonas gravely wounded by the villainous Stiles, his first urge is for his
family to flee the danger, and give up their life on a farm which Daniel has come to despise anyway.
Going alone to a lake to try to decide what to do, he falls asleep on a boat and wakes to find himself in the wild
west, in the company of such "tall tale" legends as Pecos Bill, Paul Bunyan, John Henry and Calamity Jane.
Together, they battle the same villains Daniel is facing in his "real" world, ending with a heroic confrontation in which the boy stands up
to Stiles and his henchmen, and rallies his neighbors to fight back against land grabbers who want to destroy their town.
Pecos Bill, played by Patrick Swayze.
Paul Bunyan, played by Oliver Platt.
John Henry, played by Roger Aaron Brown.
Daniel Hackett, played by Nick Stahl.
J.P. Stiles, played by Scott Glenn.
Jonas Hackett, played by Stephen Lang.
Tall Tale (also known as Tall Tale: The Unbelievable Adventures of Pecos Bill) is a 1995 American
Western adventure fantasy film directed by Jeremiah Chechik, written by Steven L.
Bloom and Robert Rodat, produced by Walt Disney Pictures and Caravan Pictures and starring Scott Glenn,
Oliver Platt, Nick Stahl, Stephen Lang, Roger Aaron Brown, Catherine O'Hara, and Patrick Swayze.
It tells the story of a young farm boy who receives aid from tall tale
figures in saving his town from a greedy developer.
Though shooting of the film was completed in 1993, it did not
get a theatrical release until March 1995.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was a box office failure,
grossing only $8.2 million on an estimated $32 million budget.